Register of the I. I. Serebrennikov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Writings, 1921-1968 (Boxes 9-17A)
  - Drafts and printed copies of articles, books, plays, and poems, 1926-1945
    - "Ocherk Ekonomicheskoi Geografii Kitaia" (Survey of the Economic Geography of China), 1926 (Box-folder 11: 11)
      Printed copy
    - "Okaiannye Dni" (Cursed Days), 1938 (Box-folder 11: 12)
    - "O Kul'tie Mertvykh" (On the Cult of the Dead), 1928 (Box-folder 11: 13)
    - "O Nedochetakh Russkikh Uchebnikov Istorii" (On the Deficiencies in Russian History Textbooks), 1942 (Box-folder 11: 14)
    - "O Propoviedi Khristianstva v Kitae v Pervye Vieka Nashei Ery" (On the Propagation of Christianity in China in the First Century of Our Era), 1945 (Box-folder 11: 15)
    - "O Russkom Iazykie, evo Iskazheniiakh i Slovotvorchestvie" (On the Russian Language, its Distortions and Word-Creation), undated (Box-folder 11: 16)
    - "O Sibirskikh Oblastnikakh" (On Siberian Autonomists), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 17)
    - "O Shkol'nom i Vysheshkol'nom Vospitanii i ob Ulichnykh Dietiakh" (On School and High-School Education and Children Out on the Street), undated (Box-folder 11: 18)
    - "Oskolki Proshlavo" (Fragments of the Past), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 19)
    - "Otvoevannoe Blagopoluchie" (Health Regained), 1933 (Box-folder 11: 20)
    - "O Tvorchestvie Chekhova" (On the Works of Chekhov), undated (Box-folder 11: 21)
    - "Pamiati D. P. Pershina" (D. P. Pershin: In Memoriam), undated (Box-folder 11: 22)
    - "Pamiati Generala G. E. Katanaeva" (General G. E. Katanaev: In Memoriam), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 23)
    - "Pamiati Professora S. M. Shirokogorova" (Professor S. M. Shirokogoroff: In Memoriam), 1940 (Box-folder 11: 24)
    - "Pamiatka Sibiriaka" (Momento of a Siberian), 1932 (Box-folder 11: 25)
      Typewritten draft, typewritten carbon copy
    - "Paskhalnyi Stol" (The Easter Table), 1944 (Box-folder 11: 26)
    - "Peitaiho,", undated (Box-folder 11: 27)
    - "Pervyi Uchenyi Buriat" (The First Educated Buryat), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 28)
    - "Pis'ma iz Tian'tszina" (Letters from Tientsin), undated (Box-folder 11: 29)
    - "Plienniki iz Khivy" (Prisoners from Khiva), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 30)
    - "Ploty iz Bordiukov po Riekie Khuan-Khe" (Rafts from Wineskins on the Hwang Ho River), undated (Box-folder 11: 31)
    - "Podkhodit i k Rossii" (It Also Suits Russia), 1938 (Box-folder 11: 32)
    - "Poet Dufu" (The Poet Tu-Fu), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 33)
    - "Poeziia v Kitaie" (Poetry in China), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 34)
      Typewritten draft, printed copy
    - "Pokhozhdeniia Moritsa Benevskavo" (The Adventures of Morris Benevsky), 1943 (Box-folder 11: 35)
    - "Po-Sibirskii" (In Siberian), undated (Box-folder 11: 36)
    - "Posliednii Podvig 'Bielavo Generala'" (The Last Exploit of the "White General"), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 37)
    - "Posliendii Put' Admirala Kolchaka" (The Last Journey of Admiral Kolchak), undated (Box-folder 11: 38)
    - "Prazdnik Piatoi Luny" (The Festival of the Fifth Moon), 1940 (Box-folder 11: 39)
    - "Presviter Ioann" (Presbyter John), 1944 (Box-folder 11: 40)
    - "Primi i Prisposob" (Adopt and Adapt), undated (Box-folder 11: 41)
    - "Prints Seotoku" (Prince Seotoku), 1942 (Box-folder 11: 42)
    - "Pristanishche Starovo Guliaki" (Shelter for an Old Reveler), 1940 (Box-folder 11: 43)
    - "Prodielki Guia" (The Escapades of Gui), undated (Box-folder 11: 44)
    - "Programmy i Doktriny" (Programs and Doctrines), undated (Box-folder 11: 45)
    - "Puteshestvie v 1863 Godu Nasliednika Tsesarevicha Nikolaia Aleksandrovicha po Oblasti Voiska Donskavo" (The Travels of the Tsarevitch Nikolai Aleksandrovich in the Region of the Don Cossacks in the Year 1863), undated (Box-folder 11: 46)
    - "Raketa Kitaia" (Chinese Rockets), 1941 (Box-folder 11: 47)
    - "Religii Kitaia" (The Religions of China), undated (Box-folder 11: 48)
    - "Relikvii Albazina" (Albazinian Relics), undated (Box-folder 11: 49)
    - "Respublika Tannu Tuva" (The Tannu Tuva Republic), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 50)
    - "Rossiiskie Kuptsy" (Russian Merchants), 1940 (Box-folder 11: 51)
    - "Rost Russkavo Zemledieliia v Trekhriech'ie" (The Growth of Russian Agriculture in the Three Rivers Region), undated (Box-folder 11: 52)
    - "Russian Investments in China,", 1933 (Box-folder 11: 53)
    - "Russians on the Amur Territory in the XVII Century,", undated (Box-folder 11: 54)
    - "Russkaia Zhenshchina v Mirovuiu Voinu" (A Russian Woman in the World War), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 55)
    - "Russkie v Man'chzhurii v Srednie Vieka" (Russians in Manchuria in the Middle Ages), undated (Box-folder 11: 56)
    - "Russkie Pokhody na Indiiu" (Russian Campaigns to India), 1942 (Box-folder 11: 57)
    - "Rybak" (The Fisherman), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 58)
    - "Sanovnik i Drovosiek" (The Official and the Woodcutter), 1939 (Box-folder 11: 59)
    - "Shaliapin v Tian'tszinie" (Chaliapin in Tientsin), 1942 (Box-folder 11: 60)
    - "Sherstianoe Proizvodstvo v Kitae" (Wool Production in China), undated (Box-folder 11: 61)
    - "The Siberian Autonomous Movement and Its Future,", 1934 (Box-folder 11: 62)
    - "Sibirskaia Relikviia v Pekinie" (A Siberian Relic in Peking), 1932 (Box-folder 11: 63)
    - "Sibirskaia Respublika" (The Siberian Republic), undated (Box-folder 11: 64)
    - "Sibirskoe Tsarstvo" (The Siberian Domain), 1932 (Box-folder 11: 65)
    - "Skazochnaia Indiia" (Legendary India), 1938 (Box-folder 11: 66)
    - "Skifi i Tatary" (Scythians and Tartars), 1938 (Box-folder 11: 67)
    - "Skotovodstvo Vneshnei Mongolii i evo Ressursy" (Pasturage Capacity of Outer Mongolia), 1936 (Box-folder 11: 68)
      Two typewritten mimeographed copies, includes English translation
    - "Slavianskie Iazyki, Narodnosti i Gosudarstva" (Slavic Languages, Nationalities and States), undated (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - "Son i Dieistvitel'nost'" (Dream and Reality), 1940 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - "Son Professora" (The Professor's Dream), undated (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - "Sovremennaia Mongoliia" (Outer Mongolia Today), 1931 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - "Stikhi, 1939-1948" (Poems, 1939-1948), undated (Box-folder 12: 5)
      Typewritten drafts, typewritten mimeographed and carbon copies
    - "Sumerki Bogov" (The Twilight of the Gods), undated (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - "Svad'ba Gorodskovo Boga" (The Wedding of City God), 1932 (Box-folder 12: 7)
      Typewritten carbon copy, includes English translation
    - "Tankas" (Tankas), 1938 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - "Teper', Kak i Prezhde" (Now as Before), 1938 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - "Tikhookeanskaia Problema s Ekonomicheskoi Tochki Zreniia" (The Pacific Problem from the Economic Point of View), 1930 (Box-folder 12: 10)
      Typewritten mimeographed copy, printed copy, includes English translation
    - "Tokto Puteshestvennik" (Tokto the Traveller), 1944 (Box-folder 12: 11)
    - "Tsarstvennyi Gost' v Chitie" (A Royal Guest in Chita), 1941 (Box-folder 12: 12)
    - "Tsygane" (Gypsies), 1938 (Box-folder 12: 13)
    - "The Turkestan-Siberian Railway,", undated (Box-folder 12: 14)
    - "Tvorchestvo I. A. Bunina" (The Works of I. A. Bunin), undated (Box-folder 12: 15)
    - "Uchitel' Mentsy" (The Teacher Mencius), 1943 (Box-folder 12: 16)
    - "Uzurpator Van Man" (The Usurper Wan Man), 1943 (Box-folder 12: 17)
    - "Van Tsiun, Fatalist i Skeptik" (Wan Tsun, Fatalist and Skeptic), 1942 (Box-folder 12: 18)
    - "V Biriul'kie" (At Spillikins), 1936 (Box-folder 12: 19)
    - "Vilikaia Legenda: Imperator Aleksandr I i Starets Fedor Kuz'mich" (A Great Legend: Emperor Alexander I and the Elder Fedor Kuz'mich), undated (Box-folder 12: 20)
    - "Velikaia Vystavka v Lintunie" (The Great Exhibition in Lintun), 1940 (Box-folder 12: 21)
      Typewritten draft, two printed copies
    - "Vino i Kitai" (Wine and China), 1938 (Box-folder 12: 22)
    - "V Khrame Neba" (At the Temple of Heaven), 1930 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - "Vladivostokskie Figury" (Vladivostok Personalities), undated (Box-folder 12: 24)
    - "Vnutrenniaia Mongoliia" (Inner Mongolia), undated (Box-folder 12: 25)
    - "Vospominaniia ob A. V. Kolchakie" (Recollections of A. V. Kolchak), undated (Box-folder 12: 26)
    - "Vozmezdie" (Retribution), 1930 (Box-folder 12: 27)
    - "Vozstanie Poliakov za Baikalom v 1866 Godu" (The Rising of the Poles on the Baikal in 1866), undated (Box-folder 12: 28)
      Handwritten outline
    - "V Stranie Uchtivykh Liudei" (In the Land of Courteous People), 1940 (Box-folder 12: 29)
    - "V Ussuriiskoi Taige" (On the Ussur Taiga), undated (Box-folder 12: 30)
      Two typewritten drafts
    - "Vvedenie" (Introduction), undated (Box-folder 12: 31)
      Typewritten carbon copy. Apparently an introduction to an unfinished work on the Revolution and Civil War in Russia.
    - "V Vodianoi Osade" (Under Siege of Water), undated (Box-folder 12: 32)
    - "Vydaiushchiesia Sibirskie Inorodtsy" (Prominent Siberian Minorities), 1942 (Box-folder 12: 33)
    - "Zabytye Poety" (Forgotten Poets), 1939 (Box-folder 12: 34)
    - "Zamietki ob Albazintsakh" (Notes on the Albazinians), undated (Box-folder 12: 35)
    - "Zanimatel "naia Kniga" (Interesting Book), 1951 (Box-folder 12: 36)
      Handwritten
    - "Zanimatel'naia Kniga – Otvety" (Interesting Book – Answers), 1952 (Box-folder 12: 37)
    - "Zanimatel'naia Kniga – Otvety" (Interesting Book – Answers), undated (Box-folder 12A: 1)
    - "Zheleznaia Doroga na Sakhaline" (Railroad in Sakhalin), undated (Box-folder 12A: 2)
    - "Zhenshchina v Russkikh Poslovitsakh i Pogovorkakh" (The Woman in Russian Proverbs and Expressions), 1943 (Box-folder 12A: 3)
    - "Znamia Ermaka" (The Banner of Ermak), 1932 (Box-folder 12A: 4)
  - Newspaper clippings of published articles by Alexandra N. and Ivan I. Serebrennikov, 1930-1968 (Box-folder 12A: 5-9)
  - Notebooks containing handwritten drafts of articles and poems by Alexandra N. and Ivan I. Serebrennikov, 1925-1946
    - Undated (Box-folder 13: 1-5)
    - 1922 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - 1925 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - 1927 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - 1936 (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - 6 notebooks, 1937 (Box-folder 14: 6-8)
    - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - 1938 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - 3 notebooks, 1939 (Box-folder 15: 3-4)
    - 4 notebooks, 1941 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - 2 notebooks, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - 5 notebooks, 1942 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 3 notebooks, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - 1944-1946 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Translations, 1920-1939
    - "Economic History of Manchuria," author unknown, 1920 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - "Egoist" (The Egoist) by Chisan Tsu Pin, 1935 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - "Iz Etiudov Chzhan Chao" (From Sketches by Chzhan-Chao), undated (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - "Iz Iaponskoi Poezii: Sbornik" (From Japanese Poetry: A Collection), undated (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - "Iz Nipponskoi Poezii: Sbornik Stikhotvorenii" (From Japanese Poetry: A Collection of Poems), undated (Box-folder 17: 1)
      Typewritten drafts, typewritten carbon and mimeographed copies
    - "Iz Vostochnykh Skazanii" (From Eastern Legends), 1939 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - "Kitaiskaia Poeziia" (Chinese Poetry), 1937 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - "Kitaiskaia Poeziia: Sbornik Stikhotvorenii" (Chinese Poetry: A Collection of Poems), volumes I and II, 1937 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - "Kitaiskie Stikhi" (Chinese Poems), 1938 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - "Kreshchenie Sv. Vladimira" (The Christening of St. Vladimir) by Karl Gavlichek, undated (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - "Tsvety Iaponskoi Poezii" (The Flowers of Japanese Poetry), 1938 (Box-folder 17A: 1)
    - "Tsvety Kitaiskoi Poezii" (The Flowers of Chinese Poetry), 1939 (Box-folder 17A: 2)
      Publishing agreement
    - "Tsvety Nipponskoi Poezii: Sbornik Stikhotvorenii" (From Nippon Poetry: A Collection of Poems), 1939-1943 (Box-folder 17A: 3)
- Subject File, 1906-1945 (Boxes 18-21)
  Correspondence, newspaper clippings, bulletins, pamphlets, charts, manuscripts of books, printed matter, and notebooks, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abyssinian arms, collection of, 1932 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Albazinians, 1906-1945 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Antikommunisticheskii Komitet Rossiiskikh Emigrantov v Severnov Kitaie (Anticommunist Committee of Russian Emigrants in Northern China), 1937-1942 (Box-folder 18: 3-4)
  - Banque Russo-Asiatique, Peking, 1932 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Chaliapin, Fedor, 1938 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - China
    - General
      Handwritten notes from various books and articles on China
      - 2 notebooks (Box-folder 18: 7-8)
      - 5 notebooks (Box-folder 19: 1-5)
    - Revolution, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Communist International, 1928 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Folk-tales--Asia, 1921 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Gantimuroff, N. P., Prince, Zabytyi Tsarevich, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    One handwritten and typewritten draft, one handwritten copy
  - Grand Fleet Battle Orders, manual of British naval tactics used by Admiral Sir John Jellicoe, translated into Russian, 1915 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    2 volumes, typewritten copy (signed by Admiral Kolchak)
  - Guins, George C., Prof., Politika Prava (Legal Policy), 1941 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Japanese propaganda bulletins, Tientsin, 1932 March (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Kulaiev, Ivan V., 1930-1941 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Obshchestvo Sibiriakov v Chekhoslovatskoi Respublike (Society of Siberians in the Czechoslovak Republic), bulletin, 1931 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Russkii Zagranichnyi Istoricheskii Arkhiv v Prage (Russian Historical Archives Abroad--In Prague), 1928 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Serebrennikov, Ivan I., "Biografiia" (Biography), 1940 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Soviet Union, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Staryi Peterburg (Old Petersburg), author unknown, handwritten extracts (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - White Russian armies in the Far East, 1936-1943 (Box-folder 21: 6)
- Miscellany, 1932-1944 and undated (Boxes 21-25)
  Banknotes, calendar, calling cards, certificates of residence, documents, financial records, greeting cards, invitations, maps, membership cards, memorabilia, memorandum book, newspapers, passports, receipts, scrapbooks, and glass negatives, arranged as listed.
  - Banknotes: Russia, pre-Revolutionary and Revolutionary eras; China (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Calendar, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Calling cards (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Certificates of residence (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Documents, correspondence and newspaper article commemorating the 40th anniversary of the literary activity of Ivan I. Serebrennikov (1941) (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Documents commemorating the 950th anniversary of the Christianization of Russia (1938) (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Financial records, 1932 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Greeting cards (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Invitations (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Maps (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - Membership cards (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Memorabilia (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Memorandum book (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - Newspapers (Box-folder 22: 10)
  - Passports (Box-folder 22: 11)
  - Receipts (Box-folder 22: 12)
  - Scrapbooks (4) (Box 23)
  - Scrapbook containing autographs, letters, photos, and postcards (Box 24)
    Includes signatures of Rimsky-Korsakov, Rabindranath Tagore, Grigorii Rasputin, Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaievitch, Admiral Kolchak, General Baron Peter von Wrangel, Maxim Gorky, and others.
  - Glass negatives (44) (Box 25)
- Photographs, 1911-1940 and undated (Photo file)
  General note
  See also: Miscellany/Glass negatives
  - 1 album with photos of Russian soldiers in the Carpathians during World War I, 1916 (Album fA)
  - 1 album with photos of White Russian soldiers and officers during the Civil War in Siberia and the Urals, and of Admiral A. V. Kolchak, 1918-1922 (Album fB)
  - 1 album with photos of atrocities committed during the Civil War in Siberia and the Urals, 1918-1922 (Album fC)
  - 1 album with photos of I. I. and A. N. Serebrennikov, Russian refugees in China, the Russian Orthodox Mission in Peking, Admiral A. V. Kolchak, Dmitrii Khorvat, and Chinese temples and buildings; and with photocopies of paintings by P. J. Safonoff depicting the Civil War in Siberia and the Urals, 1918-1922 (Album fD)
  - 1 album with photos of Lieutenant-General Baron Peter N. Wrangel's funeral in Belgrade, 1929 (Album fE)
  - 1 album with photos of Western Siberia, general, 1918-1919 (Album fF)
  - 1 album with photos and illustrations of statues and buildings in China, the Russian Orthodox Mission in Peking, the Empress Tzu-Hsi, and the Emperor Kuang-Hsu (Album fG)
  - 1 album with photos of A. N. and I. I. Serebrennikov, and statues and buildings in China, 1922 (Album fH)
  - 1 album with photos of statues and buildings in China, 1921 (Album fI)
  - 1 album with postcards depicting street scenes in Harbin, Mukden, Port Arthur, and Dairen (Manchuria); Tientsin, Peking, and Tsingtao (China); and Kyoto (Japan) (Album fJ)
  - 1 album with photos of Tientsin during the flood of 1939 and White Russian soldiers in China (Album fK)
  - 1 album with photos of buildings and landscapes in China and Manchuria, 1939 (Album fL)
  - 1 album with photos of buildings and landscapes in China, Chinese Army officers and soldiers, Marshal Feng Yu-hsiang, and Chang Tso-lin (Album fM)
  - 1 album with photos of buildings and landscapes in China, Chinese dramatic artists, and Chinese Army officers (Album fN)
  - 1 album with postcards depicting buildings and landscapes in China (Album fO)
  - 1 album with photos of A. N. and I. I. Serebrennikov and the sea-resort at Peitaiho (China), 1924 (Album fP)
  - 1 album with photos of buildings and people in Tientsin, Peking, Dairen, and Calgon, 1922-1923 (Album fQ)
  - 1 album with photos of statues, buildings, people and landscapes in Peitaiho and Peking, 1921 (Album fR)
  - 1 album with photos of A. N. and I. I. Serebrennikov, Russian refugees in China, and the sea-resort at Peitaiho, circa 1923 (Album fS)
  - 1 album with photos of statues, buildings, and landscapes in Tientsin, Peking, and Mongolia, 1923-1924 (Album fT)
  - 1 album with photos of Tientsin during the flood of 1939, foreign troops in China, and the invasion of Manchuria by the Japanese (1931-1933) (Album fU)
  - 1 album with photos of Chinese soldiers during the civil war, 1927 (Album fV)
  - 1 album with photos of Chinese funerals, 1940 (Album fW)
  - 1 album with photos of buildings and landscapes in Outer Mongolia (Album fX)
  - 1 album with photos and postcards depicting Irkutsk, Trans-Baikal, and Kyoto (Japan) (Album fY)
  - 1 album with photos of people, buildings, and landscapes in Tibet (Album fZ)
  - 1 album with photos of Russian Orthodox Mission in Peking and Russian refugees in China, 1931-1935 (Album fAA)
  - 1 album with photos of A. N. and I. I. Serebrennikov and Russian refugees in China, 1921 (Album fAB)
  - 1 album with photos of A. N. and I. I. Serebrennikov, Russian refugees in China, and Admiral A. V. Kolchak, 1911-1940 (Album fAC)
  - 1 mounted photo of I. I. Serebrennikov with members of the Council of Elders of the Russian Public Assembly in Tientsin; 1 photo of I. I. Serebrennikov, 1927 (Envelope mAD)
  - 1 photo of A. N. Serebrennikov (Envelope AE)
  - 1 autographed photo of Fedor Chaliapin (Envelope AF)
  - 16 mounted illustrations of the wives of Mongol Emperors (Envelope AG)
  - 2 mounted photos of Chinese funerals (Envelope mAH)
  - 1 mounted photo of a Chinese temple (Envelope mAI)
  - 4 mounted photos of Tibetan cities (Envelope AJ)
  - 2 mounted photos of the Chinese dramatic artist Mei Lan-fan (Envelope AK)
  - 12 postcards depicting temples and landscapes in Japan (Envelope AL)
  - 1 photo-portrait of A. V. Kolchak; 2 photos of Admiral Kolchak addressing White Russian troops on the front during the Civil War in Siberia, 1918-1922 (Envelope AM)
  - 31 photographs of troops and other individuals in Siberia and China at the time of the Russian Civil War (Envelope AN)